Anton Ohorodnyk

+1(650) 701-7762 | Sunnyvale, CA, USA | resume@aohorodnyk.com | LinkedIn: aohorodnyk | Github: aohorodnyk

Summary

Tech lead with 13+ years of experience in developing highly scalable business software solutions for millions of customers across the globe. To stay as one of the most effective engineers we need to work with businesses to deliver what they need.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer/Tech Lead at Aura

Dec 2018 - Present

- Achieved a ~90% reduction in resource utilization for the business-critical service deployed to ~70 servers by transitioning
 the service from the monolithic PHP application to the Golang microservice.
- Led a cross-functional team to introduce new functionality for digital security products to improve user engagement.
- Managed the development and implementation of the application standards to a distributed team by creating documentation, Golang framework for message processing, and multiple libraries to simplify the integration.
- Introduced new functionality to digital security products and improved user engagement by leading a cross-functional team with more than ten people.
- Saved months of development by intercepting initiative from engineering managers, architects, and product owners to build the most efficient proposal and technical solution for business.
- Found and led to fix multiple security and privacy issues across the company.

Technologies: Golang, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, NodeJS, MySQL, Memcached, Redis, Kafka, Kubernetes, Docker, AWS.

Software Architect at Ecentria

Sep 2016 - Dec 2018

- Provided technical expertise and oversight for expanding an e-commerce platform for multiple online stores.
- Oversaw a performance improvements project for a price calculation product that achieved a 90% of performance improvements by optimizing MySQL queries and PHP code.
- Architected image processing service by transitioning the product to the cloud and converting the service from a monolithic, and improving performance.
- Technically led a team of five engineers and projects with more than ten people.
- I interviewed more than four hundred candidates that helped to build a successful office with multiple teams.
- Trained and mentored junior, middle and senior engineers to help them grow and achieve their career goals.

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Symfony, React, MySQL, Solr, Redis, RabbitMQ, Cassandra, ElasticSearch, AWS.

Software Engineer at Magento, an Adobe Company

Jun 2014 - Aug 2016

- Introduced an extensible search framework for Magento 2 application with multiple implementations behind it using MySQL, Solr, and PHP.
- Managed a multi-warehouse project to simplify the integration of the Magento platform for customers with multiple
 warehouses by collaborating with architects, product management, and designers and with several cross-functional
 teams.
- Maximized performance and product stability by introducing better integration with internal databases and improvements in an architecture.
- Led teams to build new frameworks and implementations with a high level of extensibility and quality.

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Solr, Memcached, Redis, RabbitMQ, Docker, AWS.

Software Engineer at Ven Commerce Ltd

May 2013 - May 2014

- Grew new catalog view development for e-commerce platform by creating extensions for Magento platform.
- Delivered new features for a mental therapy product by collaborating with product management, designers, and several cross-functional teams and developing features in Python.
- Increased user experience and application performance by migrating a store from a custom Java implementation to the Magento platform.

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, Python, Java, MySQL, Solr, Memcached, RabbitMQ, AWS.

Education

• Master of Software Engineering, National Aviation University, Kyiv, Ukraine

2015 - 2017